<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>SERDAL</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../index.html</link>
	<description>Advancing Socio-Economics Research through Data Analytics</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 06:33:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>./../wp-content/uploads/2025/01/All-Logo-1.png</url>
	<title>SERDAL</title>
	<link>./../index.html</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Meta-analysis Training: Enhancing Research by Familiarizing with the Tool for Analyzing Analyses</title>
		<link>./../meta-analysis/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../meta-analysis/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 05:34:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../index.html?p=1382</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The UPLB Socio-Economics Research and Data Analytics Laboratory’s Meta-analysis Training, held virtually on November 14, 2024, introduced novice researchers to the key tools and techniques of meta-analysis. The one-day event, led by Dr. Arvin B. Vista from the Department of Agricultural and Applied Economics at CEM-UPLB, covered three essential topics: Introduction to Meta-analysis, Identifying and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The UPLB Socio-Economics Research and Data Analytics Laboratory’s <strong>Meta-analysis Training</strong>, held virtually on November 14, 2024, introduced novice researchers to the key tools and techniques of meta-analysis. The one-day event, led by Dr. Arvin B. Vista from the Department of Agricultural and Applied Economics at CEM-UPLB, covered three essential topics: Introduction to Meta-analysis, Identifying and Coding Meta-analysis Data, and Summarizing Meta-analysis Data.</p>
<p>The primary aim of the training was to familiarize participants with meta-analysis as a powerful research tool, enabling them to synthesize findings, improve the reliability of conclusions, and make evidence-based decisions. Attendees learned how to collect data, apply statistical techniques, and interpret results, all critical for enhancing the robustness of research outcomes.</p>
<p>With participation from researchers, students, and faculty across various universities and institutions, the training equipped attendees with the skills to incorporate meta-analytic methods into their own research. It successfully laid the groundwork for continued professional development and collaboration in meta-analysis research.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1394" src="./../wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Meta-analysis-2.png" alt="" width="2560" height="1480" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../meta-analysis/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Impact Assessment Training: A Crash Course on Designing Effective Evaluations</title>
		<link>./../impact-assessment/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../impact-assessment/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 05:31:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../index.html?p=1379</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The UPLB Socio-Economics Research and Data Analytics Laboratory’s Impact Assessment Impact Assessment Training, held virtually from November 25-27, 2024, provided an in-depth, 3-day learning experience for researchers and professionals seeking to understand and apply impact assessment methodologies. Led by Dr. Jefferson A. Arapoc, Asst. Prof. Paul Joseph B. Ramirez, and Mr. Paul Allen B. Yabut [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The UPLB Socio-Economics Research and Data Analytics Laboratory’s <strong>Impact Assessment Impact Assessment Training</strong>, held virtually from November 25-27, 2024, provided an in-depth, 3-day learning experience for researchers and professionals seeking to understand and apply impact assessment methodologies. Led by Dr. Jefferson A. Arapoc, Asst. Prof. Paul Joseph B. Ramirez, and Mr. Paul Allen B. Yabut from the UPLB Department of Economics, the training focused on experimental and quasi-experimental methods, including Randomized Control Trials (RCTs), Difference-in-Difference (DID), and Propensity Score Matching (PSM).</p>
<p>The training aimed to equip participants with the skills to design, implement, and evaluate robust impact assessments, empowering them to make evidence-based decisions in policy and program development. Through hands-on exercises and engaging discussions, attendees gained practical knowledge on how to evaluate the effectiveness of social and economic interventions, improving both the quality and transparency of data used in policymaking.</p>
<p>Participants came from diverse institutions, including government agencies, universities, and research organizations, ensuring broad applicability of the content. By the end of the program, attendees were more confident in their ability to conduct high-quality impact assessments, contributing to more informed, data-driven decision-making in their respective fields.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1397" src="./../wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Impact-Assessment-2.png" alt="" width="2770" height="1314" /> <img decoding="async" class="alignnone wp-image-1398" src="./../wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Impact-Assessment-3.png" alt="" width="1361" height="270" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../impact-assessment/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Empowering Researchers with Essential Data Management Skills</title>
		<link>./../data-management/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../data-management/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 05:30:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../index.html?p=1376</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[UPLB SERDAL’s Training Series: Empowering Researchers with Essential Data Management Skills The UPLB Socio-Economics Research and Data Analytics Laboratory (UPLB SERDAL), launched its highly anticipated Training Series on Socio-Economics Data Management. This training series was designed to enhance the data management capabilities of researchers, students, and professionals in the socio-economics field. The series, conducted via [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>UPLB SERDAL’s Training Series: Empowering Researchers with Essential Data Management Skills</strong></p>
<p>The UPLB Socio-Economics Research and Data Analytics Laboratory (UPLB SERDAL), launched its highly anticipated <strong>Training Series on Socio-Economics Data Management. </strong>This training series was designed to enhance the data management capabilities of researchers, students, and professionals in the socio-economics field. The series, conducted via Zoom, comprised three comprehensive training sessions:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Fundamentals of Research Data Management</strong> (Aug 12, 2024) laid the groundwork for understanding core data management concepts, the data lifecycle, and best practices in managing research data effectively.</li>
<li><strong>Search, Storage, Security, and Sharing Research Data</strong> (Aug 14, 2024) addressed key topics such as metadata management, choosing the right data storage solutions, ensuring data security and privacy, and implementing strategies for securely sharing data within research networks.</li>
<li><strong>Practical Data Analysis Workshop</strong> (Aug 16, 2024) offered hands-on experience with data analysis techniques, including visualization tools and Excel applications, equipping participants with practical skills to interpret and present data effectively.</li>
</ol>
<p>The sessions were led by Asst. Prof. Reginald Neil C. Recario from the Institute of Computer Science at CAS-UPLB and Dr. Jefferson A. Arapoc from the Department of Economics at CEM-UPLB. It was interactive and focused on real-world applications, empowering participants to apply their learning in socio-economics research</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1391" src="./../wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Data-Management-3.2.png" alt="" width="2880" height="1800" /> <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1390" src="./../wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Data-Management-3.1.png" alt="" width="2880" height="1800" /> <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1389" src="./../wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Data-Management-2.png" alt="" width="2880" height="1800" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../data-management/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Open Data Training: Promoting Data Accessibility in the Digital Age</title>
		<link>./../open-data/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../open-data/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 05:28:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../index.html?p=1373</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The UPLB Socio-Economics Research and Data Analytics Laboratory’s Open Data Training, held virtually from November 6-8, 2024, aimed to promote open data practices among researchers, students, and professionals across various institutions. The 3-day event introduced participants to the concept of open data and provided hands-on training in navigating the CKAN (Comprehensive Knowledge Archive Network) platform, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The UPLB Socio-Economics Research and Data Analytics Laboratory’s <strong>Open Data Training</strong>, held virtually from November 6-8, 2024, aimed to promote open data practices among researchers, students, and professionals across various institutions. The 3-day event introduced participants to the concept of open data and provided hands-on training in navigating the CKAN (Comprehensive Knowledge Archive Network) platform, a key tool for open data management.</p>
<p>The training, led by Dr. Concepcion L. Khan of the Institute of Computer Science at CAS-UPLB, covered crucial topics such as the significance of open data in advancing research, improving decision-making, and promoting collaboration. Participants learned how open data practices can transform data accessibility and foster transparency in research initiatives. A key session focused on overcoming the challenges of implementing open data initiatives in the Philippines.</p>
<p>The training not only offered theoretical insights but also provided participants with practical experience using open data platforms. The CKAN live demonstration and hands-on session allowed participants to apply what they learned in real-time.</p>
<p>This initiative is expected to foster a growing network of open data advocates, driving innovation and knowledge-sharing in the Philippines and beyond.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../open-data/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Futures Thinking Training Workshop: Shaping the Futures of the AANR Sector</title>
		<link>./../futures-thinking/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../futures-thinking/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 05:26:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../index.html?p=1370</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The UPLB Socio-Economics Research and Data Analytics Laboratory organized a comprehensive 3-day training workshop on Futures Thinking, held on January 14 to 16, 2025, at the Conference Room, Obdulia F. Sison Hall, UPLB. The workshop aimed to enhance participants’ understanding of futures thinking and foresight, focusing on critical aspects of strategic planning in the agriculture, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The UPLB Socio-Economics Research and Data Analytics Laboratory organized a comprehensive 3-day training workshop on <strong>Futures Thinking</strong>, held on January 14 to 16, 2025, at the Conference Room, Obdulia F. Sison Hall, UPLB. The workshop aimed to enhance participants’ understanding of futures thinking and foresight, focusing on critical aspects of strategic planning in the agriculture, aquatic, and natural resources (AANR) sector. The workshop covered various topics, including: Introduction to Futures Thinking, Futures Thinking in the AANR, Agri-Systems Approach to Futures Thinking and Problem Tree Analysis, Scanning, Reflexive Foresight and Causal Layered Analysis (CLA), Emerging Trends and Futures Wheel, Scenario Building, Backcasting and Strategic Policy Thinking, and Strategic Foresight and Planning.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The training discussions were spearheaded by Dr. Melodee Marciana E. De Castro, project leader of SERDAL Phase 2, and supported by the project team members: Asst. Prof. Luisito C. Abueg, Asst. Prof. Geny F. Lapiña, and Mr. Paul Kenneth B. Maghirang. The sessions were further enriched by the expertise of distinguished resource speakers from other university colleges, including Dr. Aileen V. Lapitan and Dr. Hadji C. Jalotjot from the College of Public Affairs and Development, as well as Dr. Rodmyr F. Datoon from the College of Agriculture and Food Science.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The training workshop targeted representatives from the Socio-Economic Research and Data Analytics Centers (SERDACs), along with their satellite centers. The participating universities included Central Luzon State University, Visayas State University, University of Southeastern Philippines, Western Mindanao State University, and University of Southern Mindanao. Additionally, faculty members and researchers from CEM-UPLB were present, enriching the diversity of perspectives. Representatives from DOST-PCAARRD also participated, ensuring alignment with the SERDAL and SERDAC initiatives.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-1407 aligncenter" src="./../wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Futures-Thinking-2.jpg" alt="" width="1341" height="688" /><br />
<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-1408 aligncenter" src="./../wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Futures-Thinking-3.jpg" alt="" width="1350" height="826" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../futures-thinking/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>NVivo Training Workshop: Mastering Qualitative Research</title>
		<link>./../nvivo/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../nvivo/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 05:23:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../index.html?p=1367</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The UPLB Socio-Economics Research and Data Analytics Laboratory’s NVivo Training Workshop, conducted on December 9, 2024, in a hybrid setup, was led by Dr. Nicamil K. Sanchez. He introduced participants to NVivo 15’s core features, including basic data organization and coding, as well as advanced tools like query functions and data visualization. Aimed at researchers, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The UPLB Socio-Economics Research and Data Analytics Laboratory’s <strong>NVivo Training Workshop, </strong>conducted on December 9, 2024, in a hybrid setup, was led by Dr. Nicamil K. Sanchez. He introduced participants to NVivo 15’s core features, including basic data organization and coding, as well as advanced tools like query functions and data visualization. Aimed at researchers, faculty, and staff from Socio-Economic Research and Data Analytics Centers (SERDACs), the event focused on enhancing participants’ qualitative data analysis skills. Attendees gained practical experience in using NVivo to improve their research processes.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-1401 aligncenter" src="./../wp-content/uploads/2025/03/NVivo-2.png" alt="" width="1338" height="721" /><br />
<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-1368 aligncenter" src="./../wp-content/uploads/2025/03/NVivo-1.jpg" alt="" width="1348" height="1012" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../nvivo/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hello world!</title>
		<link>./../hello-world/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../hello-world/index.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 15:44:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../index.html?p=1</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Welcome to WordPress. This is your first post. Edit or delete it, then start writing!]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Welcome to WordPress. This is your first post. Edit or delete it, then start writing!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../hello-world/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
